Email: xiup.li@mail.utoronto.ca Tel: 647-675-7510

25 Carlton Street, apt.2801, Toronto ON, M5B 1L4

Xiuping (Molly) Li

Professional Summary

Master of Economics graduate with proven records in quantitative and qualitative analysis while being proficient in Microsoft Office, VBA, SQL and Python. Highly motivated investment analyst associate and market analyst assistant with excellent relationship management skills, reporting and analyses experience. Highly passionate fast learner with excellent oral and written communication skills while being currently enrolled in CFA Level I.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Toronto ON

Aug 2016 – Jun 2017

M.A. in Economics

- Top 5% in Applied Financial Risk Management, International Financial Economics and Macroeconomic Theory
- Participated in Strategy in Action Case Competition to advance business analysis and in-depth research skills
- Specializations: econometrics, finance, risk management; Matlab, Excel/VBA, Stata

University of British Columbia, Vancouver BC

Sep 2014 – May 2016

B.A. Major in Mathematics and Minor in Economics

- GPA 4.0/4.0; Dean's List; Chancellor's Scholar Awards; Faculty of Arts International Students Scholarship
- Specializations: Mathematics and Economics; MATLAB; Python; Latex

EXPERIENCE

University of Toronto, Department of Economics, Toronto, ON

Sep 2016 – May 2017

Teaching Assistant, ECO220Y2 – Quantitative Methods of Economics

- Delivered Excel Modules tutorials weekly for an undergraduate class size of 40 to enhance the proficiency of classes
- Tested the relationship between mutual fund asset growth and the growth in the TSX index using Excel Data Analysis
- Analyzed and summarized historical data of real GDP, population and index of human capital using Excel Pivot Table
- Developed Excel Macros and VBA based on data types, condition statements, and loops

HSBC Genius Training Program, China

Aug – Sep 2014

Investment Analyst Associate

- Clarified, translated and processed technical information and financial data using SQL and Excel to assist Investment Analyst solve projects issues, develop reports, and make decisions
- Provided analytical support and insights in support of relative product and trading development, including but not limited to products and portfolio management, profitability analyses and customer analytics
- Collaborated with team members to develop innovative solutions to meet changing client and senior analyst needs

China Telecom, China

Dec 2013 - Dec 2014

Market Analyst Assistant

- Assisted the retail store manager in organizing, planning and implementing strategy to ensure objectives are met
- Compiled and analyzed market data using Excel and SQL, and prepared summary documents to report to shareholders
- Conducted in-depth research on potential markets, created sales growth reports using Excel, analyzed and interpreted retail data to quantify China's telecom business growth

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Risk Management Project (Excel VBA)

- Evaluated Operational Risk, Market and Credit risk with the knowledge of Pricing model, Value-at-Risk type models, Capital models, Behavioral and Stress-Testing models; tested the accuracy of the models' implementation,
- Analyzed and reported market risks of trading portfolios, using Parametric VaR measure and Excel VBA
- Developed VBA procedures to calculate Historical VaR, Expected Shortfall, and EVT Tail VaR of trading portfolios

Business Analytics (Python)

- Analyzed and investigated Giant Telco Company's profit margin, and created presentation with preliminary analysis
- Developed a predictive model for a major clinic to understand returning patients, and created an analytics solution
- Conducted exploratory data analysis to identify data issues, created simple analysis to assess hypothesis, calculated feature importance using machine learning, and translated predictive models into business measurement

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE/INTERESTS

- Volunteer: Assistant in ArtStarts in School, Assistant in Golden Panda Film Festival, Chair of Linda Voluntary Group
- Interests: international travel, biking, jogging and hiking
- Language: fluent in Mandarin and English
- Certifications: SAS Base Programming, SAS Advance Programming